Guide to the Henry Lewis Stimson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Speeches, Writings, Statements, 1888-1975; Series III
  - Writings: On Active Service
    - Interviews with Bundy
      - Pp. 176-186, regarding atomic energy, war crimes, treatment of Germany, Russia, war casualties, Doolittle Board, army officers entering politics, bacteriological warfare compared to atomic bomb, 1946 July 9 (Box 188, Folder 12)
        See also: box 186, folder 3a.
      - Pp. 187-189, regarding trusteeships, 1946 July 15 (Box 188, Folder 13)
      - Part II, pp. 75-84, regarding Hoover, the Philippines, 1946 May 29 (Box 188, Folder 14)
      - Pp. 190-196, regarding campaign for Governor, 1946 July 24 (Box 188, Folder 15)
      - Pp. 197-213, regarding War Department, Monnet, Truman Smith, Henry Parkman, selective service, Hillman and labor, Office of Production Management, Benedict Crowell, T. Roosevelt, 1946 September 9 (Box 188, Folder 16)
      - Pp. 214-229, regarding War Department, White House press conferences, Clarence Streit--Grenville Clark, Patton and Adler, military training camps, General Marshall, Woodring and Johnson, 1946 September 11 (Box 188, Folder 17)
      - Pp. 230-244, regarding politics 1912-1915, Tariff, Depression of 1929, 1946 September 17 (Box 188, Folder 18)
      - Pp. 245-259, regarding 1940-1945, [1946 October 16?] (Box 188, Folder 19)
    - Interview with Rudolph Winnacker, skeleton outline of events in life of Henry Lewis Stimson, includes two outlines for or from interview, pp. 1-30, 1946 April 29 (Box 188, Folder 20)
    - Outlines (Box 188, Folder 21)
    - Memo regarding early days in the State Department, Jan-Mar 1929 (Box 188, Folder 22)
    - Memo: "How I Became Acquainted with Franklin Roosevelt" (Box 188, Folder 23)
    - Memo by Henry Lewis Stimson, "World War II: Choice Tidbits in the Third Person", 1946 May 15 (Box 188, Folder 24)
    - Memo by Henry Lewis Stimson, "Attitude to the Approach to War in 1941", 1946 September 6 (Box 188, Folder 25)
    - Memos by Bundy regarding the atomic bomb, 1947 March (Box 188, Folder 26)
    - Two drafts for introductory chapter submitted by Bundy, 1946 June 13, July 12 (Box 188, Folder 27)
    - Foreword suggestions by Arthur W. Page and draft of second paragraph of the introduction (Box 188, Folder 28)
    - Drafts by Henry Lewis Stimson for introductory chapters, regarding childhood, education, and early law practice (Box 188, Folder 29)
    - Duplicates of drafts for introductory chapter (Box 188, Folder 30)
    - Final copy and draft of "Afterword" by Henry Lewis Stimson (Box 188, Folder 31)
    - Draft for chapter "Governor General of the Philippines," by Bundy (Box 188, Folder 32)
    - Draft for opening of chapter "The Army and the Navy," by Henry Lewis Stimson (Box 188, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous notes by Bundy and Henry Lewis Stimson (Box 188, Folder 34)
    - Mailing lists (Box 188, Folder 35)
  - Writings: My Vacations
    - Preliminary notes, incomplete set of chapter drafts, and publication notes, 1949 (Box 188, Folder 36)
    - Memo book of trip to Colorado, 1890 July-August (Box 188, Folder 37)
    - Notebook of trips to Montana, 1891-1894 (Box 188, Folder 38)
    - Mailing list for My Vacations (Box 188, Folder 39)
  - Writings: Correspondence with Harper and Brothers regarding On Active Service and My Vacations, 1944-1951 (Box 189, Folder 1-14)
  - Other Public Statements
    - Memorandum for 29th Assembly District Bulletin, Undated (Box 190, Folder 1)
    - Statement at hearing on the bill to amend the Tax Law in relation to taxation of mortgage indebtedness before the New York State Senate Committee on Taxation and Retrenchment, 1903 (Box 190, Folder 2)
    - Statements in the campaign for Governor of New York, 1910 October-November (Box 190, Folder 3)
    - Two brief statements from the War Department, 1911 June (Box 190, Folder 4)
    - Statements regarding The American Sugar Refining Company, 1911 June 15 (Box 190, Folder 5)
    - Annual Report of the Secretary of War, printed copy only, 1911 December 4 (Box 190, Folder 6)
    - Henry Lewis Stimson statement to the press regarding the Army Appropriations Bill, 1912 May 27 (Box 190, Folder 7)
    - Statement to the press regarding the death of Wilbur Wright, 1912 May 30 (Box 190, Folder 8)
    - Statement regarding strike of employees of the Panama Railroad Company, 1912 July 1 (Box 190, Folder 9)
    - Statement by Henry Lewis Stimson after passage of final army appropriations bill, 1912 August 23 (Box 190, Folder 10)
    - Statement regarding Dam construction on the Connecticut River, 1913 January 23 (Box 190, Folder 11)
    - Statement from the Office of the Secretary of War, 1913 February (Box 190, Folder 12)
    - Statement regarding ordering out the troops to protect suffragette parade in Washington, DC, 1913 March 7 (Box 190, Folder 13)
    - Republican Club of the City of New York, reports of the Committee on National Affairs, 1913 Apr, May (Box 190, Folder 14)
    - Republican Club of the City of New York, reports of the Committee on National Affairs, "The Military Needs of Our Country", 1915 February (Box 190, Folder 15)
    - Three statements regarding the work of the New York Constitutional Convention, 1915 August-October (Box 190, Folder 16)
    - Report of the Sub-committee on National Defense of the Committee on National Affairs of the Republican Club of New York City, [1916?] (Box 190, Folder 17)
    - Interview on Mr. Root's strength as a candidate before the people of New York and a memorandum on the same subject, 1916 (Box 190, Folder 18)
    - Statement regarding Governor Whitman's budget proposals, 1916 (Box 190, Folder 19)
    - Statement regarding the constitutionality of National Universal Military Training, 1916 February (Box 190, Folder 20)
    - Statement on death of Lindley Garrison, 1916 February 10 (Box 190, Folder 21)
    - Statement in response to Wilson's note to the belligerent powers, 1916 December 22 (Box 190, Folder 22)
    - Statement regarding national support for war effort, 1917 April 12 (Box 190, Folder 23)
    - Statement regarding National Budget Committee Report, 1919 October 9 (Box 190, Folder 24)
    - Statement for use of the Roosevelt Memorial Association, 1919 October 10 (Box 190, Folder 25)
    - Republican Club, National Affairs Committee, Sub-committee on the Conduct of the War and Military Policy, 1919-1920 March (Box 190, Folder 26-27)
    - Statement regarding Soldiers' Bonus written for Mrs. Vanderlip of the National League of Women Voters, 1922 September 18 (Box 190, Folder 28)
    - Statement regarding The Independent Voters' League, 1922 October 16 (Box 190, Folder 29)
    - Opinion relative to pending legislative program for the regulation of public utilities for the Institution of American Busines, 1923 March (Box 190, Folder 30)
    - Statement to newspapers as counsel for Benedict Crowell, 1934 January 31 (Box 190, Folder 31)
    - Statement to Officers and Boards of Governors of Social Clubs in New York City regarding Prohibition, 1924 May 5 (Box 190, Folder 32)
    - Minute for records of the Circuit Court of Appeals in memory of Judge Emile Lacombe, 1925 February 6 (Box 190, Folder 33)
    - "Memorandum on the Evidence Bearing on the Question Whether a Fair Plebicite Can Now Be Held in Tacna Arica," sent to Secretary of State, 1926 June 3 (Box 190, Folder 34)
    - Statement for the press regarding political conditions in the Philippine Islands, 1926 September 8 (Box 190, Folder 35)
    - Memorandum on sugested co-operation between the Executive and Legislative Departments of the Philippine Government, 1926 September 9 (Box 190, Folder 36)
    - Interview given at San Francisco regarding the Philippines, 1926 October 20 (Box 190, Folder 37)
    - Statement regarding Nicaragua, 1927 May 24 (Box 190, Folder 38)
    - Statement regarding appointment as Governor General of the Philippines, 1927 December 2 (Box 190, Folder 39)
    - Statement and notes for the press during term as Governor General of the Philippines, 1928 March-December (Box 190, Folder 40)
    - Annual Report of the Governor General of the Philippines, 1929 March 1 (Box 190, Folder 41)
    - Oath of Office as Secretary of State, 1929 March 28 (Box 190, Folder 42)
    - Two statements for the Press, 1929 March 29, 31 (Box 190, Folder 43)
    - Statement before the House Ways and Means Committee on the Dangers of Tariff Restriction Upon Imports from the Philippine Islands, particularly with reference to sugar, printed copy only, 1929 April 17 (Box 190, Folder 44)
    - Nine statements for the press, 1929 May 16-September 14 (Box 190, Folder 45)
    - Statement at an executive meeting of the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations regarding Cuba, 1929 September 25 (Box 190, Folder 46)
    - Duplicate of statement before the executive meeting of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and the stenographic transcript, 1929 September 25 (Box 190, Folder 47)
    - Notes and reference material used at executive meeting of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee regarding Cuba, 1929 September 25 (Box 190, Folder 48)
    - Testimony before Senate Subcommittee of Commerce Committee regarding Extension of coastwise shipping laws of the United States to the Philippine Islands, 1929 October 24 (Box 191, Folder 1)
    - Drafts of comments made to the Japanese Delegation when they came to Washington on their way to the London Naval Conference, 1929 December (Box 191, Folder 2)
    - Draft of statement on leaving Great Britain after the London Naval Conference, 1930 April 23 (Box 191, Folder 3)
    - Remarks before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee regarding ratification of the London Naval Treaty, 1930 May 12 (Box 191, Folder 4)
    - Testimony before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee Hearing regarding the London Naval Treaty, 1930 May 13-14 (Box 191, Folder 5-6)
    - Memoranda prepared for the Senate Foreign Relations Committee Hearing testimony regarding the London Naval Treaty, 1930 May 12-14 (Box 191, Folder 7)
    - Printed coy of testimony before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee Hearings, 1930 May (Box 191, Folder 8)
    - Statement before the Senate Committee on Insular Affairs regarding Philippine Independence, outlines and printed copy, 1930 May 22 (Box 191, Folder 9)
    - State Department press release regarding the London Naval Treaty, 1930 June 6 (Box 191, Folder 10)
    - Statement before the Senate Committee on Immigration regarding suspension of general immigration for two years, printed copy only, 1930 December 18 (Box 191, Folder 11)
    - Statement on death of Joseph Cotton, 1931 March 10 (Box 191, Folder 12)
    - Notes used at press conference regarding disarmament, 1932 January 18 (Box 191, Folder 13)
    - Notes prepared for press conference at Woodley regarding Sino-Japanese situation, 1932 March 12 (Box 191, Folder 14)
    - Transcript of press conference, Geneva, Switzerland, 1932 April 16 (Box 191, Folder 15)
    - Statement for the press on leaving Geneva, 1932 April 30 (Box 191, Folder 16)
    - Statement in defense of Aide Capt. E. Regnier, 1932 May-June (Box 191, Folder 17)
    - Four summaries of Henry Lewis Stimson statements at his press conferences regarding debts and reparations, 1932 June-July (Box 191, Folder 18)
    - "Arms Embargo Resolution and Neutrality," printed copy of memorandum left with House Committee on Foreign Affairs at the conclusion of testimony, 1933 February 8 (Box 191, Folder 19)
    - Statement for Christian Science Monitor regarding Foreign Service, 1934 February 13 (Box 191, Folder 20)
    - Four memos on neutrality and regulation of munitons, [1934?], 1934 March-June (Box 191, Folder 21)
    - Memo: the effect of Philippine Independence on the balance of power in Asia for Council on Foreign Relations Philippine Group, [1934-1935?] (Box 191, Folder 22)
    - Statement written in support of London for president, but never made public, outline and notes also, 1936 (Box 191, Folder 23)
    - Statement on death of Elihu Root, 1937 February 7 (Box 191, Folder 24)
    - Statement sent to Senator Burke on the Supreme Court, 1937 July 16 (Box 191, Folder 25)
    - Outline for discussion: The Far Eastern Policy of the U.S., [1938 Feb?] (Box 191, Folder 26)
    - Message for transmittal to Lord Cecil to be read at a mass meeting in London in support of Japanese Boycott, 1938 February 7 (Box 191, Folder 27)
    - Memo of topics for talks with Congressmen, 1938 March 28 (Box 191, Folder 28)
    - Annual statement of the President of the Association of the Bar, 1938 May 10 (Box 191, Folder 29)
    - Three memos regarding Munich agreement, 1938 September 28-29 (Box 191, Folder 30)
    - Statement before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee on the Neutrality Act, 1939 April 5 (Box 191, Folder 31)
    - Statement to the Stop Arming Japan Rally in Greater Boston, 1939 April 22 (Box 191, Folder 32)
    - Statement at Hearing of Senate Committee on Military Affairs on nomination of Secretary of War, memos, notes, and drafts., 1940 July 2 (Box 191, Folder 33)
    - Two press releases, 1940 July 17 (Box 191, Folder 34)
    - Statements before the Deficiency Sub-committee of the House Appropriations Committee on the Second Supplemental National Appropriations Bill for 1941, drafts and extracts from Congressional Record only, 1940 July 24, 26 (Box 191, Folder 35)
    - Statement before the House Military Affairs Committee Hearings on selective compulstory military training and service, 1940 July 31 (Box 191, Folder 36)
    - Statement before Joint Hearing of House Ways and Means Committee and Senate Finance Committee, 1940 August 9 (Box 192, Folder 1)
    - Transcripts of two press conferences, 1940 September 19, 26 (Box 192, Folder 2)
    - Transcripts of four press conferences, 1940 October 3, 10, 17, 24 (Box 192, Folder 3)
    - Transcripts of two press conferences, 1940 November 14, 26 (Box 192, Folder 4)
    - Transcripts of two press conferences, 1940 December 12, 19 (Box 192, Folder 5)
    - Christmas greetings to the U.S. Army, first draft, 1940 December 25 (Box 192, Folder 6)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1941 January 9 (Box 192, Folder 7)
    - Hearings before the House Committee on Foreign Affairs on the Lend-Lease Bill, 1941 January 16-17 (Box 192, Folder 8)
    - Transcript of press confernece, 1941 January 23 (Box 192, Folder 9)
    - Statement and testimony before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee hearing on Lend-Lease Bill, 1941 January 29 (Box 192, Folder 10)
    - Three drafts of testimony before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee hearing on Lend-Lease Bill, 1941 January 29 (Box 192, Folder 11)
    - Notes for testimony before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee hearing on Lend-Lease Bill, 1941 January 29 (Box 192, Folder 12)
    - Testimony before executive session of Senate Foreign Relations Committee hearing on S275 to Promote the Defense of the United States, printed copy only, 1941 January 30 (Box 192, Folder 13)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1941 February 6 (Box 192, Folder 14)
    - Statement to members of the American Youth Congress regarding colored population in the army, printed copy only, 1941 February 10 (Box 192, Folder 15)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1941 February 27 (Box 192, Folder 16)
    - Testimony before a Subcommittee of the House Committee on Appropriations regarding the Defense Aid Supplemental Appropriation Bill, 1941 extract from the Congressional Record only, 1941 March 13 (Box 192, Folder 17)
    - Notes for Appearance before House Committee (Executive Session) in regard to aid to Britain, probably before House Subcommittee of Appropriations Committee regarding Defense Aid Supplemental Appropriation Bill--Mar 13,1941 (Box 192, Folder 18)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1941 March 14 (Box 192, Folder 19)
    - Statement before Subcommittee of the Senate Appropriations Committee regarding the Defense Aid Supplemental Appropriaion Bill, 1941, 1941 March 20 (Box 192, Folder 20)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1941 March 27 (Box 192, Folder 21)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1941 April 3 (Box 192, Folder 22)
    - Statement on the death of Senator Morris Sheppard, 1941 April 9 (Box 192, Folder 23)
    - Statement before Truman Committee of Senate, 1941 April 15 (Box 192, Folder 24)
    - Transcripts of three press conferences, 1941 May 15, 22, 29 (Box 192, Folder 25)
    - Transcripts of two press conferences, 1941 June 5, 9 (Box 192, Folder 26)
    - Testimony before the House Committee on Rivers and Harbors hearing on the Improvement of the Great Lakes-St. Lawrence Seaway and Power Project, 1941 June 17 (Box 192, Folder 27)
    - Transcripts of two press conferences, 1941 July 3, 24 (Box 192, Folder 28)
    - Press statement regarding the Wheeler Circular, 1941 July 29 (Box 192, Folder 29)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1941 July 31 (Box 192, Folder 30)
    - Transcript of two press conferences, 1941 September 11, 18 (Box 192, Folder 31)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1941 October 1 (Box 192, Folder 32)
    - Statement before House Foreign Affairs Committee Hearing on Arming American Merchant Vessels, 1941 October 13 (Box 192, Folder 33)
    - Statement before Subcommittee of Senate Appropriations Committee Hearing on Lend-Lease, notes and printed copy. Notes include material possibly for House testimony Sep 1941., 1941 October 14 (Box 192, Folder 34)
    - Transcripts of three press conferences, 1941 October 16, 23, 30 (Box 192, Folder 35)
    - Transcripts of two press conferences, 1941 November 6, 27 (Box 192, Folder 36)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1941 December 5 (Box 192, Folder 37)
    - Statement at press conference regarding Pearl Harbor, 1941 December 11 (Box 192, Folder 38)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1941 December 18 (Box 192, Folder 39)
    - Annual report of the Secretary of War, printed copy only, 1941 (Box 192, Folder 40)
    - Statement on the Army War College Program, 1942 December 17 (Box 192, Folder 41)
    - Excerpt from press conference, 1942 December 31 (Box 192, Folder 42)
    - Testimony before the House Foreign Affairs Committee Hearing on extension of the Lend-Lease Act, extracts from the Congressional Record only, 1943 February 8 (Box 192, Folder 43)
    - Memorandum for the press regarding Army Day, 1943 March 3 (Box 192, Folder 44)
    - War review and summary of Tunisian campaign at press conference, ditto copies only, 1943 March 13 (Box 192, Folder 45)
    - Statement for Pentagon War Fund meeting, 1943 October 18 (Box 192, Folder 46)
    - Recorded message of Christmas greetings to the Troops, 1943 October 26 (Box 192, Folder 47)
    - Transcript of press conference, 1943 December 28 (Box 192, Folder 48)
    - Statement regarding the War Department's operations of the nation's railroads, 1943 December 28 (Box 192, Folder 49)
    - Testimony before the Senate Military Affairs Committee Hearing on the National Service Bill, 1944 January 19 (Box 192, Folder 50)
    - Testimony before the House Committee on Foreign Affairs on Extension of Lend-Lease Act, 1944 March 3 (Box 192, Folder 51)
    - Statement before Senate Committee on Banking and Currency, 1944 March 28 (Box 192, Folder 52)
    - Joint Statement by Stimson, Knox, Land regarding manpower needs in the armed services and industry, typed copy from the Washington Post only, 1944 April 21 (Box 192, Folder 53)
    - Statement before the House Select Committee on Post-War Military policy, mimeographed copy only, 1944 April 25 (Box 192, Folder 54)
    - Testimony before the House Banking and Currency Committee Hearing on the extension of the Emergency Price Control Act, 1944 May 2 (Box 192, Folder 55)
    - Independence Day statement, 1944 July 4 (Box 192, Folder 56)
    - Recorded message of Christmas greeetings to the troops, 1944 October 13 (Box 192, Folder 57)
    - Statement at news conference regarding death of Sir John Dill, 1944 November 9 (Box 192, Folder 58)
    - Opening statement at press conference, 1944 December 21 (Box 192, Folder 59)
    - Statement at meeting with the Secretary of the Navy and leading educators of the country regarding compulsory military training during peace time, transcript only, 1944 December 29 (Box 192, Folder 60)
    - Testimony before Senate Military Affairs Committee Hearing on mobilization of civilian manpower, 1945 February 6 (Box 193, Folder 1)
    - Testimony before House Foreign Affairs Committee Hearing on the Extension of Lend-Lease Act, 1945 February 14 (Box 193, Folder 2)
    - Statements on the death of Franklin Roosevelt, 1945 April 12, 13 (Box 193, Folder 3)
    - Two statements regarding surrender of Germany, one to General Eisenhower, 1945 May 8 (Box 193, Folder 4)
    - Testimony before the Senate Committee on Postwar Military Policy Hearing on universal military training, 1945 June 15 (Box 193, Folder 5)
    - Statement regarding the atomic bomb, 1945 August 6,7 (Box 193, Folder 6)
    - Statement regarding the Pearl Harbor Disaster, [1945 August 29] (Box 193, Folder 7)
    - Statement at the Cabinet meeting regarding military training, 1945 September 7 (Box 193, Folder 8)
    - Citations awarding Alexander Surles the Distinguished Service Medal and William H. Kyle and Kenneth Kreps each the Legion of Merit, 1945 September 17 (Box 193, Folder 9)
    - Citations awarding Distinguished Service Medal to Robert Patterson, John J. McCloy, Robert Lovett, and Harvey Bundy, 1945 September 18 (Box 193, Folder 10)
    - Citations awarding Medal of Merit to John W. Martyn, statement at final news conference, 1945 September 19 (Box 193, Folder 11)
    - Statement to the Joint Committee on the Investigation of the Pearl Harbor Attack, mimeographed copy only, 1946 March (Box 193, Folder 12)
    - Deposition for the International Military Tribunal for the Far East, 1946 June 7 (Box 193, Folder 13)
    - Statement on Philippine Independence, 1946 June 14 (Box 193, Folder 14)
    - Appearance on television on 81st birthday, 1948 September 21 (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - The Reminiscences of Henry Stimson, typed script from an interview with Allan Nevins and Dean Albertson for the Oral History Project, 1949 September (Box 193, Folder 16)
    - Outline of Early Memories of Alfred Stearns and problems of Phillips Academy, Circa 1950 April (Box 193, Folder 17)
- Special Subjects, Series IV
  - Republican Party, 1894-1904
    - List of voters in both election districts, unidentified list of names, [1894] (Box 194, Folder 1)
    - Report of canvass in 28th electoral district, New York City (Box 194, Folder 2)
    - Revised membership rolls of the 28th electoral district (Box 194, Folder 2)
    - Republican Association and circular to voters of 27th assembly district from the District Republican Club, 1897 (Box 194, Folder 2)
    - Copy of new primary law, Republican circular, lists of registered voters, 1898 (Box 194, Folder 3)
    - 21st election district of the 27th assembly district, notes on nominations of candidates, primary ballot and other official party business, 1898 (Box 194, Folder 4)
    - Lists--canvasses of registered voters, registered Republicans, 1898 (Box 194, Folder 5)
    - Circulars for voter registration, 1899 (Box 194, Folder 6)
    - Circular regarding Republican primary with sample ballot, Henry Lewis Stimson handwritten notes regarding this ballot for a campaign speech, list of contributors, 1900 (Box 194, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified district Republican items prior to 1902 (Box 194, Folder 8)
    - List of contributors to campaign fund, 1902 (Box 194, Folder 9)
    - List of contributors and possible contributors to Republican Club Fund and correspondence of others regarding contributors, 1903 (Box 194, Folder 10)